Guide to the Elizabeth Jenks Clark Collection of Margaret Anderson
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- General Correspondence, 1932-1981, undated; Series I; 4.17; (10 boxes)
  - Margaret Anderson
    - Lauterstein and Lauterstein
      See: Modjesha, Marylka
    - Leblanc, Georgette, 1939-1942, undated (Box 7, Folder 111)
      Includes Georgette Leblanc's will and letters from Leblanc to Josephine Plowsday
      See also: Plowsday, Josephine ("Tippy")
    - Levesque, Angèle, circa 1955 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Lympany, Moura, 1964-1971 (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - Maeterlinck, Maurice, undated (Box 7, Folder 114)
      Translation by Jackie Porter
    - Martin, Jean-Claude, 1967 August 15 (Box 7, Folder 115)
    - Matthews, Donna, 1971 January 26 (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Mintz, Steven, 1972 October 31 (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - Murphy, Noël Haskins, undated
      See: Murphy, Noël Haskins
    - New York Times Company
      See: Lank, Thomas
    - New Yorker, 1971 July 17 (Box 7, Folder 118)
    - Palmer, Jean Anderson and Mary Karinsky, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 119)
    - Peters, Fritz, 1966, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 120)
      Includes letter from The University of New Mexico Press to Fritz Peters
    - Plowsday, Josephine ("Tippy"), 1931-1940, circa 1958 (Box 7, Folder 121)
      See also:Leblanc, Georgette
    - Porter, Jackie, after 1970 (Box 7, Folder 122)
    - Powell, ___, 1971 December 8 (Box 7, Folder 123)
    - Random House
      See: Rothenberg, Jerome
    - Read, Ivan, 1968 November 13 (Box 7, Folder 124)
    - Reynolds, Florence, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 125)
    - Rock, Yvan, 1961-1971 (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - Rothenberg, Jerome, 1972, undated (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - Sarason, Bertram, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Schonberg, Harold, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 129)
    - Selley, Margaret (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Siegal, George and Lillian, 1956, 1970-1973, undated (Box 7, Folder 131-132)
    - Solano, Solita, before 1930-1973, undated (Box 7, Folder 133)
      See also: Clark, Elizabeth Jenks; Solano, Solita
      Includes notes on editing My Thirty Year's War
    - Steloff, Frances, 1956 July (Box 7, Folder 134)
    - [Stirling], Monica, undated (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Svendsen, Clara, 1971 June 24 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Tanner, Allen, 1926, 1970, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 137)
      Includes photographs of Tanner
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1949, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Tilden, Gladys and Bill, 1966, undated (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - Toklas, Alice B., 1952-1964 (Box 7, Folder 140-142)
    - Turbyulle, Mark, 1970 May 30 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - United States. Department of State, New York, 1953 January 28 (Box 8, Folder 144)
      Regards The French Service of the Voice of America
    - Wheeler, Monroe, 1952 February 13
      See: Wheeler, Monroe
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - Yale University Library, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 146)
    - Unidentified and first names only, undated (Box 8, Folder 147-148)
    - Regarding permissions, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - Notes and unidentified drafts of outgoing letters, circa 1953-1973, undated (Box 8, Folder 150-152)
  - Third Party Correspondence
    This subseries is arranged under three headings: Correspondence to Elizabeth Jenks Clark and Mathilda Hills, To and from Solita Solano, and Other Correspondents. Each grouping arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - To Elizabeth Jenks Clark and Mathilda Hills
      - American Women's Volunteer Services, 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 153-157)
        Includes meeting minutes and clippings
      - Beaumont, Germaine, 1957-1963, undated (Box 8, Folder 158)
      - Bedford, Sybille, 1968, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 159)
      - Clark, Joseph, Jr., undated (Box 8, Folder 160)
      - Codman, Florence, 1955, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 161)
        Includes photographs of Codman and unidentified friends
      - Cunard, Nancy, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 162)
      - Currier-Briggs, Michael, 1973-1980 (Box 8, Folder 163)
      - Fielding, Daphne, 1973-1975, undated (Box 9, Folder 164)
      - Flanner, Hildegarde, 1943-1957, undated (Box 9, Folder 165)
      - Flanner, Janet, circa 1970-1976, undated (Box 9, Folder 166)
      - Hulme, Kathryn, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 167)
        Includes photographs of Kathryn Hulme and friends in Hawaii
      - Levesque, Angèle, 1978-1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 168)
      - Lympany, Moura, 1964-1969 (Box 9, Folder 169)
      - Morgan, Anne, 1945-1947 (Box 9, Folder 170)
      - Pabeser, Jeane, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 171)
      - Petrova, Olga, 1976 February 10 (Box 9, Folder 172)
      - Roch, Yvonne, 1976 January 16 (Box 9, Folder 173)
      - Serrure, Monique, 1956 June 19 (Box 9, Folder 174)
      - Tanner, Allen, 1978 February 7 (Box 9, Folder 175)
      - Tilden, Helen, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 176)
      - Unidentified, circa 1950 (Box 9, Folder 177)
        Includes Elizabeth Jenks Clark's writings and William P. Jenks obituary, 1955
    - To and from Solita Solano
      - Clark, Elizabeth Jenks, 1949, 1970, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 178)
      - Davidson, Louise, 1962-1974 (Box 9, Folder 179)
      - Fielding, Xan, undated (Box 9, Folder 180)
      - Flanner, Janet, circa 1948, undated (Box 9, Folder 181)
      - Heap, Jane, 1935 March 26, undated (Box 9, Folder 182)
      - Huckle, Dorothea, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 183)
      - Hulme, Kathryn, 1966-1973 (Box 9, Folder 184-185)
      - Nabokov, Vladamir and Vera, 1968-1975, undated (Box 9, Folder 186-187)
      - Plowsday, Josephine, 1932, undated (Box 9, Folder 188)
      - Porter, Jackie, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 189)
        Accompanied by Margaret Anderson's 1967 prepared suicide note to friends
      - Stcherbine, Kathleen, 1945-1947 (Box 9, Folder 190)
      - Troxel, Dorothy, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 191-192)
        Includes photograph of grave site of Larry [Troxel]
      - Other correspondents to Solita Solano, 1960-1973, undated (Box 10, Folder 193)
        Includes Solita Solano's writings and printed material
    - Other correspondents
      - Antheil, George to Jane Heap, undated (Box 10, Folder 194)
      - Caruso, Dorothy; Goddard, Gladys to Vera Paige and various, 1948-1955 (Box 10, Folder 195-196)
        Includes photographs of Margaret Anderson, Jane Heap, and Dorothy Caruso; regards Georges Ivanovitch Gurdjieff
      - Various to Davidson, Louise, 1945-1947 (Box 10, Folder 197)
      - Eliot, T.S. to Jane Heap, 1941 October 25 (Box 10, Folder 198)
      - Unidentified to Gladys Goddard, 1952 January 9 (Box 10, Folder 199)
        See: Caruso, Dorothy; Goddard, Gladys to Vera Paige and various
      - Plowsday, Josephine to Georgette Leblanc, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 200)
      - Stein, Gertrude to [Janet Scudder?], circa 1932 (Box 10, Folder 201)
      - Tilden, Gladys to Earle Huckle, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 202)
      - Tyner, Chloe to Mathilda Hills, 1980-1981, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 203)
        Includes Jane Heap obituary,1964
      - "Lolly" to "Jannie", 1969 (Box 10, Folder 204)
- Writings, 1914-1973; Series II; 2.92; (7 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is organized into two subseries: Books and Other Writings.
  Books contains writing drafts, correspondence, photographs, research notes, contracts, and other papers relating to Margaret Anderson's books and an unfinished and unpublished work tentatively titled "Collection of Memoires and Private Papers"("My Collection"). Solita Solano often edited Anderson's writings and her holograph notes can be found on drafts. Most of the correspondence in the series reflects Anderson's solicitation of advice from friends throughout her writing process. A smaller portion of the correspondence regards publication details.
  "Collection of Memoires and Private Papers"("My Collection") was intended to be a comprehensive collection of letters and short writings by Anderson and she completed much of the work of copying and organizing her correspondence and writings. Anderson annotated the manuscript heavily. The letters comprising the nine-volume manuscript are copies of original letters filed elsewhere in the collection.
  Anderson often used working titles that differed from the final title. The Fiery Fountains was referred to as "Love Story," "Whoever Loves," and 'This Thing Called Love." The Strange Necessity was referred to as "The Art of Life."
  Other Writings contains writing drafts, correspondence, notes and other papers documenting published and unpublished articles and essays by Margaret Anderson. Untitled writings, notes, a small amount of correspondence, and a cartoon from the Little Review are filed at the end of the series.
  Cross references have been provided between Series I, Correspondence and this series for all correspondence with Anderson. Cross references have not been provided for Elizabeth Jenks Clark and Solita Solano because of the volume of their correspondence throughout both series.
  - Books
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - The Fiery Fountains
      - Drafts
        - Preface for reprint by Janet Flanner, draft, typescript, undated (Box 11, Folder 205)
        - Draft, typescript, undated (Box 11, Folder 206)
        - Correction notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 207)
      - Photographs with captions, undated (Box 11, Folder 208-209)
      - Correspondence
        - Caruso, Gloria, undated (Box 11, Folder 210)
        - Codman, Florence, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 211)
          See also: Schaffner, John to Florence Codman
        - Cowley, Malcolm
          See: Viking Press
        - Darrow, Ags and Dorothy Kramer, undated (Box 11, Folder 212)
        - Davidson, Louise, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 213)
        - Foster, Jeannette, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 214)
        - Hecht, Rose, 1959 April (Box 11, Folder 215)
        - Huckle, Dorothy, 1959 September 5 (Box 11, Folder 216)
        - Hulme, Kathryn, 1956-1959 (Box 11, Folder 217)
          Includes letters to Solita Solano
        - Kramer, Dorothy
          See: Darrow, Ags and Dorothy Kramer
        - Murphy, Noël Haskins, undated (Box 11, Folder 218)
        - Schaffner, John to Florence Codman, 1958 April 28 (Box 11, Folder 219)
          See also: Codman, Florence
        - Solano, Solita, circa 1929, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 220)
        - Tanner, Allen, 1958-1960 (Box 11, Folder 221)
        - Tilden, Gladys, 1959 August 13 (Box 11, Folder 222)
        - Viking Press, 1958 June 17 (Box 11, Folder 223)
        - Wheeler, Monroe, 1952 February 13 (Box 11, Folder 224)
        - General correspondence, copies of reviews and notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 225)
      - Reviews, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 226)
    - Forbidden Fires
      - Drafts, fragments, typescript and holograph, circa 1972 (Box 11, Folder 227-230)
      - Drafts, typescript, undated (Box 12, Folder 231-233)
        Accompanied by Anderson's notes concerning friends' reactions, an undated letter from Coburn Britton and letter to Nigel Nicolson, 1973 January 3
    - The Little Review Anthology, contract, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 234)
    - "Collection of Memoires and Private Papers" ("My Collection")
      - Introduction, preface and volumes 1-4, 1914-1972 (Box 12, Folder 235-239)
        Includes photographs
      - Volumes 5-9, 1914-1972 (Box 13, Folder 240-245)
      - Introduction draft edited by Solita Solano, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 246)
      - Draft fragments, typescript and holograph, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 247-250)
      - Notes and correspondence drafts for inclusion in manuscript, 1942-1967, undated (Box 14, Folder 251-252)
      - Correspondence
        - Currier-Briggs, Michael, 1966-1973, undated (Box 14, Folder 253-257)
          Includes drafts; some letters also regard The Strange Necessity
    - My Thirty Year's War
      - Notes regarding editing, before 1930 (Box 14, Folder 258)
      - Reviews, 1930
    - My Thirty Year's War; The Fiery Fountains; The Strange Necessity. Horizon Press, 3 volume set, 1970
      - Contract, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 259)
      - General correspondence in response to publication, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 260)
      - Lists of people to receive books, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 261)
      - Book jackets, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 262)
    - "Resume," typescript draft, undated
      See: "Elegy for Georgette," draft, holograph and typescript
    - The Strange Necessity
      - Draft, typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 263-264)
      - Draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 265-266)
      - Fragment, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 267)
      - Correspondence
        - Britton, Coburn, 1969 December 13 (Box 15, Folder 268)
        - Christoffersen, ___, 1970 June 26 (Box 15, Folder 269)
        - Nicolson, Nigel, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 270)
        - Peters, Fritz, 1970 January 7, undated (Box 15, Folder 271)
        - Unidentified, 1970 December 12 (Box 15, Folder 272)
    - The Unknowable Gurdjieff
      - Research notes
        - Solita Solano's unedited notes, 1935-1938 (Box 15, Folder 273-276)
          Includes 1938 letters to Kathryn Hulme and Alice Rohrer
        - Solita Solano's edited notes, photographs and clippings, 1934, 1979, undated (Box 15, Folder 277-280)
        - Other notes, 1941, 1943-1944 (Box 15, Folder 281-282)
        - Other notes, fragments, undated (Box 15, Folder 283)
      - Notes on John Bennet's visit, by Margaret Anderson and Dorothy Caruso, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 284)
        Includes photocopy of letter from Vera Nabokov to Ezra Pound, 1953 September 26
      - Correspondence
        - Dale, Ernest, 1969 January 20 (Box 16, Folder 285)
        - de Cande, Elizabeth, 1971 June 3 (Box 16, Folder 286)
        - Harcourt, Brace and World, 1961 December 1 (Box 16, Folder 287)
        - Nathanson, Anne, 1972 August 14 (Box 16, Folder 288)
        - Selley, Margaret, 1971, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 289)
        - Stuart, Vincent, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 290)
        - Regarding taxes, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 291)
      - Reviews, 1962-1963 (Box 16, Folder 292)
      - "Daring Questions for Thinking People" from American Fabrics, undated
  - Other Writings
    This subseries is organized under three headings: titled works, untitled writings, and other material. Titled works are arranged alphabetically by title and untitled writings and other material are arranged by material type.
    - Titled works
      - "The Art of Prose," draft, typescript, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 293)
      - "The Chalet Rose," from The American Abroad, tear sheets, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 293a)
      - "Chambre d'Hotel," galley, circa 1972
      - "Chambre d'Hotel" and "Notebook," drafts, typescript, circa 1972 (Box 16, Folder 294-295)
        Includes letter to Dorothy and Helen Heitz regarding "My Collection;"1949 August 7 letter from Dorothy Caruso to Solita Solano and Elizabeth Jenks Clark; and 1972 letter to Margaret Anderson from Dorothy Kramer
      - "A Life for a Life," advertisement for unpublished book, undated (Box 16, Folder 296)
      - "Night Thoughts," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 297)
    - Untitled writings
      - Draft fragments, undated (Box 16, Folder 298)
      - Notes re. Little Review Vol 1-11. New York: Kraus Reprint Corporation, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 299)
      - Notes on Dorothy Caruso, draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 300)
      - Notes on Alice B. Toklas, Gertrude Stein, Monique, Georgette Leblanc, and Dorothy Caruso, circa 1950, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 301)
      - Notes on deaths of Allen Tanner, Mary Garden, Dorothy Caruso, and Jane Heap and other notes, after 1955 (Box 16, Folder 302)
      - Notes on Little Review, 1967 August (Box 16, Folder 303)
      - Notes on Little Review nine-volume reprint, undated (Box 16, Folder 304)
      - Notes on unpublished book idea, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 305)
      - Miscellaneous notes, after 1970 (Box 16, Folder 306)
    - Other material
      - "For Coby", undated (Box 16, Folder 307)
      - Rejection letters, 1952-1968 (Box 16, Folder 308)
      - Fan mail and questions, 1952-1972 (Box 16, Folder 309)
      - Royalties and finances, 1967-1970 (Box 16, Folder 310)
      - Empty folder (Box 16, Folder 311)
      - "Light occupations of the editor, while there is nothing to edit," cartoon from Little Review, undated
- Writings of Others, 1920-1972, undated; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series III, Writings of Others, is arranged alphabetically by author.
  This series contains writings by Margaret Anderson's friends. The bulk is writings and drawings by Georgette Leblanc.
  - Bryer, Jackson. "Little Review History," draft, typescript and correspondence, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 312)
  - Davidson, Louise. "The Baroness" and "This is No Life," drafts, typescript with drawing and note, undated (Box 17, Folder 313)
  - Fielding, Daphne. "Emerald and Nancy: Lady Cunard and Her Daughter," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 314)
  - Heap, Jane. "The Little Review: Art and the Law," printed version, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 314a)
  - Leblanc, Georgette
    - "Cette Autre Chose," printed version, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 315)
    - Chapter from "La Machine à Courage," translation by Solita Solano and Margaret Anderson, draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 316)
    - Souvenirs: My Life with Maeterlinck Volumes 1 and 2, translation by Solita Solano and Margaret Anderson, draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 317-320)
    - Poems, drafts, undated (Box 17, Folder 321)
    - "The Art of Drawing," draft, typescript and original drawings, undated (Box 17, Folder 322)
  - Solano, Solita
    - "Elegy for Georgette," draft, holograph and typescript, undated, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 323)
      Includes copies of various writings by others and Margaret Anderson's September 3, 1972 "Resume," typescript draft
    - "Visit to Baroness Blixen," draft, typescript, June 1962 (Box 17, Folder 324)
- Photographs, circa 1914-1979; Series IV; 2.09; (5 boxes)
  Series IV, Photographs, is organized into five subseries: From Little Review, Photographers, Individuals, Places, and Albums.
  This series contains photographs and negatives of Margaret Anderson, her family and friends, places, and individuals that were involved in the literary circle of the Little Review. Photographs from the Little Review era are annotated by Anderson. The work of notable portrait photographers Berenice Abbott, Man Ray, and Victor George are found in the series. Photograph albums assembled by Margaret Anderson consist of photographs of people and places from throughout her life. Many but not all of the negatives have accompanying prints.
  Photographs appear elsewhere in the collection and are noted where they occur.
  - From Little Review, circa 1914-1930 (Box 18, Folder 325)
    Portraits of Juan Gris, William Carlos Williams, George Antheil, Francis Picabia, Djuna Barnes, Allen Tanner, Stanislaus Szukalski, Mark Turbyfill, Constantin Brancusi, Ossip Zadkine, Jacques Lipchitz, Ben Hecht, Cedric Morris, James Joyce, Gertrude Stein, Pavel Tchelitchew, Sherwood Anderson, Ernest Hemingway; accompanied by Little Review cover signed by Henri Gaudier-Brzeska
  - Photographers
    - Abbott, Berenice, undated (Box 18, Folder 326)
      Portraits of Solita Solano, James Joyce, Janet Flanner, George Antheil, Margaret Anderson, Jane Heap, Jean Cocteau, Djuna Barnes, and Alexander Berkman
    - George, Victor, 1921 (Box 18, Folder 327)
      Portraits of Margaret Anderson
    - Ray, Man, undated (Box 18, Folder 328)
      Portraits of Margaret Anderson, Solita Solano, Pablo Picasso, Georges Braque, Francis Picabia, Rene Matisse, André Derain, and Marcel Duchamp (reproduction)
  - Individuals
    - Anderson, Margaret, 1919-circa 1970 (Box 18, Folder 329-331)
      Includes broken glass plate negative and images of Georgette Leblanc
    - Anderson, Margaret and family, 1886-1970 (Box 18, Folder 332-335)
      Includes reproductions of photographs of Margaret Anderson's family lent to Mathilda Hills by Lois Anderson Karinsky
    - Anderson, Margaret and friends, 1919-1973 (Box 19, Folder 336-340)
      Consists of photographs of Marylka Modjesha, Elizabeth Jenks Clark, Agnes Yarnell, Solita Solano, Fritz Peters, Gladys Tilden, Dorothea Huckle, Allen Tanner, Kathryn Hulme, Lou Habets; and the grave sites of Monique Serrure, Georgette Leblanc and Margaret Anderson.
    - Beaton, Cecil, undated (Box 19, Folder 341)
    - Beaumont, Germaine, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 342)
    - Boyle, Kay, circa 1943 (Box 19, Folder 343)
    - Caruso, Dorothy and Gloria, 1921-1942, undated (Box 19, Folder 344)
      Includes photographs of Margaret Anderson and Dorothy Caruso's studio
    - Cendrars, Blaise
      See: Levesque, Angèle and Blaise Cendrars
    - Chervachdje (Prince and Princess), circa 1940 (Box 19, Folder 345)
    - Clark, Elizabeth Jenks, 1930-1962 (Box 19, Folder 346-350)
      Includes photographs of Elizabeth Jenks Clark's sculptures; Clark's family; Solita Solano; unidentified friends; and photographs from Tucson, AZ and Northeast Harbor, ME
    - Clark, Elizabeth Jenks; Solano, Solita, circa 1955-1975 (Box 19, Folder 351)
    - Clark, Elizabeth Jenks; Solano, Solita, circa 1955-1975 (Box 20, Folder 352)
    - Cunard, Nancy, 1931-1932 (Box 20, Folder 353)
      Includes photograph of portrait
    - Davidson, Louise, circa 1938, undated (Box 20, Folder 354)
    - Delbos, Andrée, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 355)
    - Fielding, Daphne, 1968, undated (Box 20, Folder 356)
    - Flanner, Janet, 1965, undated (Box 20, Folder 357)
    - Fresnay, Pierre, undated (Box 20, Folder 358)
    - Garden, Mary, undated (Box 20, Folder 359)
    - Empty folder (Box 20, Folder 360)
    - Gurdjieff, Georges Ivanovitch, circa 1930-1956 (Box 20, Folder 361)
    - Heap, Jane, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 362)
    - Hulme, Kathryn, undated (Box 20, Folder 363)
    - Leblanc, Georgette, 1897-1932, undated (Box 20, Folder 364-367)
      Includes negatives of Georgette Leblanc's will
    - Levesque, Angèle and Blaise Cendrars, circa 1935, circa 1940, 1949, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 368)
      Includes postcard to Elizabeth Jenks Clark
    - Ligon, Barbara, circa 1960 (Box 20, Folder 369)
    - Modjesha, Marylka, 1947 September (Box 20, Folder 370)
    - Murphy, Noël Haskins, circa 1930, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 371)
    - Plowsday, Josephine, undated (Box 20, Folder 372)
    - Scudder, Janet, circa 1932, undated (Box 20, Folder 373)
    - Solano, Solita, 1915-1970 (Box 21, Folder 374-378)
      Includes Kathryn Hulme, Alice Rohrer, Janet Flanner, Kathryn Hulme; and Solano's family and house in Orgeval and Croton-on-Hudson, NY
    - Yarnall, Agnes Lepage, circa 1970 (Box 21, Folder 379)
  - Places, 1955-circa 1979 (Box 21, Folder 380-387)
    Includes photographs of house in Orgeval, France; Northeast Harbor, ME; Sudbury, MA; and many photographs include Solano and Clark's cat
  - Two photograph albums, 1914-circa 1970 (Box 22, Folder 388-392)
- Sound Recordings, 1976-1983; Series V; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  This series contains sound recordings of interviews with friends and family of Margaret Anderson.
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Reference copies are available and filed in the folders.
  - Interviews
    - Banke, Esther, 1976 February 7 (Box 23, Folder 393)
      Conducted by Jane Purse in Chicago. Esther Banke is the sister of Marie Banke or "Jim", Jane Heap's teacher at the Lewis Institute.
    - Karinsky, Lois Anderson, 1978 May (Box 23, Folder 394-401)
      Conducted in Sante Fe, New Mexico.
    - Levesque, Angèle, 1977-1978, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 402-409)
    - Treseder, Florence Mack, 1976 February 1 (Box 24, Folder 409a)
      Conducted by Jane Purse in Hollywood, CA. Florence Mack Treseder is the niece of Florence Reynolds.
    - Treseder, Florence Mack and David Greggory, undated (Box 24, Folder 409b)
- Personal Papers, 1941-1973; Series VI; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Deed of trust for Margaret Anderson Trust, 1943 June 1 (Box 25, Folder 410)
  - Diary writings, circa 1933 (Box 25, Folder 411)
  - Notebooks, circa 1965-1970 (Box 25, Folder 412)